And one can of cocoa
extract, if you would.
[CLERK 19A]
Very good, sir.
[MAN 19A]
Playing "Lord of Crime?"
[LOUIS grunts]
[MAN 19B]
Yes. My boy got carried away
and apparently injured
one of the other lads.
Seems imitating Robin Hood
is very popular these days.
But this Lord of Crime,
he's nothing but a
bloodthirsty hoodlum.
[MAN 19A]
That he is.
I wish the children would
start emulating this young MP,
instead of those
bloody mobsters.
[LOUIS]
MP?
[PARLIAMENT MEMBER 19A]
Young upstart!
[PARLIAMENT MEMBER 19B]
Who do you think you are?
[SPEAKER 19A]
We will have order!
Gentlemen, quiet, please!
Mister Whiteley
still has the floor.
You may continue.
Oi, he's coming out!
[REPORTERS shouting]
[REPORTER 19B]
Mister Whiteley!
Doesn't this make the third time
you've proposed
your election reform bill?
Assuming it even makes it
through the House of Commons,
it's all but certain to be
killed when it reaches
the House of Lords!
Isn't that right?
[WHITELEY]
Before proposing the bill,
I knew there would be
this level of opposition.
However, for the
sake of this nation,
the right to vote must
be extended to everyone,
including working
class citizens.
You have my word--
whatever it takes, I'll see that
the measure passes this season.
[REPORTER 19A] How will
you deal with the opposition
within the House of Commons?
[REPORTER 19C] And how will you
wear down the House of Lords?
Do you have some
secret strategy?
[WHITELEY] I will convince
them somehow. Quote me on that.
Please, sir. Step inside.
[WHITELEY]
Of course, thank you.
[grunts]
That smell... Gunpowder?
Surely not.
It's a bomb! Get away
from the carriage! Quickly!
[CITIZENS screaming]
[WHITELEY grunting]
[CITIZENS murmuring]
[gasps]
[MAN 19C grunts]
Tell me, who in
the blazes hired you?
Whatever do you mean, sir?
[POLICEMAN 19A] Mister
Whiteley! Are you all right?
[WHITELEY]
Yes.
But never mind me,
search this man.
[POLICEMAN 19B]
I don't understand.
Why this man, sir?
On numerous occasions,
I've had the chance to
address large crowds of people.
However, when I look out,
I can instantly tell by their
faces what they're thinking--
their inner feelings.
Faces brimming
with expectations,
pinning their hopes on me.
Faces of those who are
doubtful, sceptical of me.
And faces like his,
that wish only death upon me.
Look! I found some spare
fuses inside his bag!
[CITIZENS gasp]
Nicely done, Mister Whiteley.
My dear constituents!
Even when faced with
this sort of violence,
I will never back down!
I will get the reform bill
passed and that's a promise!
Mark my words!
Achieving equality
is not only my mission--
it's the dream shared by the
people of this great nation!
[CITIZENS gasp, cheer]
[CITIZEN 19A]
Whiteley!
[CITIZEN 19B]
Adam Whiteley!
[CITIZEN 19C] You are
the delegate of the people!
[LOUIS] "Assassination
attempt on MP Whiteley."
Some say he staged it
himself to gain publicity.
"Is Britain's white
knight nothing more
than a swindler
peddling 'equality'?"
As far as I'm able to tell,
there's nothing dubious about
Mister Whiteley or his message.
No, he's a man
of impeccable integrity.
The question is,
how far does he intend to stride
under this banner
of social equality?
William, what do you think?
The bomber was a mobster
and most likely hired
by the House of Lords.
Should the Yard
make the connection,
Whiteley will become
the standard bearer
for a popular revolution.
Election reform will be swift,
and the prime minister's
post will be his.
[WILLIAM] On the other hand,
political and social unrest
within the country
will only increase.
And the lives of many
people could easily be lost
in the ensuing
violence and mayhem.
Whether or not
that is the outcome
he is secretly hoping for
is a matter I would
like to test him on.
"Equality." Yeah, right.
Heard a lot of politicians
talking about
those lofty ideals;
none of them were on the level.
[WILLIAM]
No.
We cannot say with any
certainty he's like the others.
[MORAN]
Hm?
Depending on how
Whiteley reacts,
this land might see
equality at last
without the need for us to
become involved any further.
Oi, it's time for your supper--
[gasps]
[plate clatters]
[POLICEMAN 19C]
Wha--? Blimey!
Somebody call a doctor!
The bomber died while
in police custody?
How is that even possible?
[PATERSON grunts] He was
stabbed through the throat.
The guard discovered
a pen within the cell.
He'd already died
from blood loss.
Based on the nature of death,
the CID hasn't ruled it
as suicide or murder yet.
What is going on here?
I'm sorry such a terrible mishap
occurred in my own station,
Mister Whiteley. Truly.
[WHITELEY] It's hard to believe
a mobster working for money
would take his own
life out of loyalty
for the House of Lords.
If it was homicide,
then the only conclusion
is that there is a
collaborator within the Yard.
[WHITELEY]
Chief Inspector Paterson,
it is going to be
much more difficult now
to determine who
hired our bomber.
It gives me pause
to request this,
but in regards to
the investigation,
I would like to
select which personnel
are involved with this case.
Hand-picked by you?
[WHITELEY]
Yes.
But I assure you, I am a
rather good judge of character.
[EMPLOYEE 19A]
This article simply won't do.
We are a high-class--
Oh, good morning,
Mister President, sir.
[EMPLOYEES murmuring]
A very pleasant morning
to you, Lord Milverton.
Was your meeting at the
House of Lords productive?
[MILVERTON]
Yes.
A shame they didn't
come to me sooner, though.
And not after sending
low-level thugs
to carry out a failed
assassination plot.
If they had succeeded
in killing Whiteley,
he would have died a hero--
a martyr for the great
cause of equality.
What an utter pack of fools.
Still, there may
be hope for them.
The House of Lords
did see fit to hire me,
so I'll dispose of him.
And my approach will
be, shall we say, different.
Then, I would assume...
[MILVERTON]
Yes.
I will destroy
Whiteley's good name,
casting him down from
his righteous spot.
Right then, when
the white knight falls,
I'll be watching from
the best seat in the house.
[WILLIAM]
It's time, Albert.
I trust you've
prepared everything?
Tomorrow we'll see what
Mister Whiteley is made of.
[ALBERT]
Mm.
[ALBERT] On that note, I have
the documents you requested.
[WILLIAM] Excellent work,
brother. Thank you.
[ALBERT grunts]
I know this is
an essential step.
I only hope, like us,
he can move forward
despite the pain inflicted.
[WILLIAM grunts]
[WHITELEY] Maggie,
where's the morning edition?
Oh, well, actually it's--
Oh, I see now.
More frontpage denigration
from my critics, no surprise.
But really, it
doesn't bother me.
Kindly bring it here.
Oh, very well. But don't
say I didn't warn you.
[ROBINSON] Good morning
to you, Mister Whiteley.
[WHITELEY] Inspector Robinson
and Sturridge, same to you.
Come, sit down and
join us for breakfast.
We've only just started eating.
[ROBINSON]
You eat breakfast together
like one big happy
family, I see.
Rather cosy, I must confess.
This is pretty much
standard procedure here.
I'm sure you'll get used to our
ways quite quickly, Inspector.
Maggie makes the
most delicious pies.
Wait till you have one.
[ROBINSON]
I certainly look forward to it.
[SAM]
Good morning, Adam.
We have guests.
You are Mister Robinson
and Sturridge?
And good morning
to you, too, Marcus.
[STURRIDGE]
Ah, good to see you, Sam.
Hope you don't mind,
but we'll be joining you
for breakfast today.
Where's Maggie?
Most likely making a
big fuss and snipping out
any defamation towards me
in this morning's paper.
Don't tease. She's
just worried about you.
[SAM sighs] There's no
end to the threatening
letters you receive.
And only yesterday, there
was an attempt on your life.
And she's not the
only one. I worry, too.
[WHITELEY]
Listen.
I understand your
concerns, Samuel.
However, I'm not the sort
of man who allows his will
to be shaped by pressure.
Or backs down to cowards
who level threats.
I know, but still...
[WHITELEY]
As soon as my bill passes,
things will change
for the better. Trust me.
A fair and equal world is coming
where people can truly be free.
I trust you. But I just--
We know you're proud of him!
That brother of
yours is going to
single-handedly
change this nation!
That's why we've taken
on the responsibility
of making sure he's protected.
Things have proved challenging,
but our investigation into
the threats is proceeding,
so please, try not to worry.
[SAM grunts]
[WHITELEY]
You're sure?
I wish you'd be able to
come to the ceremony today.
I'm ever sorry. Do come
back safely. Promise me?
Of course, Sam. Off I go, then.
He has the inspectors
looking after him.
He should be perfectly fine.
The dream we worked
tirelessly to bring about
has nearly come to fruition.
You will be making
your remarks after
Mayor Dempster briefly
says a few words.
One last thing.
After the ceremony is
completed and park is opened,
the guests you invited
will be welcome to see it.
Excellent news. Thank you.
I can hardly wait.
[MARCUS gasps]
No.
This is all wrong.
What the devil is going on here?
This isn't what we planned.
Those are the MPs
who opposed his bill!
What're they doing here?
If they haven't yet,
soon they'll talk the mayor
into siding with them.
This whole ceremony
will turn into
a public execution
of Mister Whiteley!
[DEMPSTER] Ladies and gentlemen,
I am Mayor Dempster.
I trust you're doing
well this fine day.
Standing here in front of you,
it brings me great
pleasure to announce
this lovely park
is now open to the public.
But looking back,
the journey of completing it,
well, it certainly wasn't an
easy task to say the least.
Public safety concerns,
pollution issues,
but clearly, the most
challenging setback
was none other than the
"champion of the people,"
MP Adam Whiteley!
To begin with, he revoked
the plans for this park
after they had
already been approved!
[TOWNSMAN 19A]
Whiteley did that?
[TOWNSMAN 19B]
Is that true?
[DEMPSTER]
Not only that--
he then had the nerve to force
newly designed plans on us.
Drawn up by him, of course!
And do you know the result?
Not only did the park far exceed
its original allocated budget,
but additionally,
all construction efforts
nearly came to a
complete and utter halt!
Despite the
obstacles he created,
we were undaunted and saw the
project to completion for you.
To give the people this
beautiful public space.
Yes, there was a great
amount of influence
in its creation, but it
wasn't from Mister Whiteley.
If you want to know who
you should really thank,
it's the members of
parliament with us today!
[TOWNSPEOPLE murmur]
And now, I'll ask Mister Spencer
to say a few words on
behalf of these gentlemen.
My fellow Londoners,
before I begin, let me say
it pains me to bring this up
on such a glorious day.
But I must take this opportunity
to address something.
Concerning the park
and his election reform bill,
the man you see
sitting over there
has been every bit a dictator.
He pushed for his vision,
despite not reaching consensus
in the House of Commons,
and chose to submit the
bill of his own accord.
Furthermore, there has
been reformation dialogue
proceeding behind closed doors.
But the efforts of the
House of Lords has been derailed
by none other
than Mister Whiteley!
In short, the person who's
standing in the way of reform
is none other than
Mister Whiteley himself!
[MARCUS] They're
placing the blame on him?
This is simply absurd!
Regular negotiations
with the House of Lords
would have taken at least 30
years before reforms passed!
He is risking his life
and going alone
for the benefit of
all the citizenry!
Good people, I ask only that you
please decide for yourselves.
Who here on this stage
is truly acting in the best
interest of the citizens
and not simply paying
them lip service?
Consider this
for God and country!
[DEMPSTER] Thank you very
much for that, Mister Spencer.
What he said, is it true?
I'm not sure.
Let's wait and hear
what Whiteley has to say.
[DEMPSTER]
Now we will hear some remarks
from the infamous
Mister Whiteley.
Right.
What you heard from the
Mayor and Mister Spencer
concerning this park,
I would like to take a
moment to respond to.
All of it is the truth.
[TOWNSPEOPLE gasp, murmur]
[TOWNSMAN 19E]
What?
[TOWNSMAN 19F]
Are you serious?
[TOWNSWOMAN 19B]
You aren't denying it?
[TOWNSMAN 19G]
We believed in you!
My ego compelled me to step in
with my own plans for the park.
Also, I was aware
that both houses
were at work behind the scenes
making efforts toward
bringing about reforms.
However, I nonetheless proceeded
to propose my own bill.
Lastly, I would like to
apologise for the delay
regarding the park's completion.
The blame is on me.
And that is all I have
to say on the matter.
[TOWNSMAN 19H]
What? That's all?
[TOWNSMAN 19I]
You haven't explained a thing!
[TOWNSMAN 19J] He must've been
involved in something shady,
otherwise he would
have said more.
[TOWNSMAN 19K]
My word, what a disappointment.
[MARCUS]
But why?
Why didn't you
defend yourself, sir?
[WHITELEY]
There's no need.
[MARCUS] But you could've
outlined your intentions
when designing this place!
What you wanted to achieve!
If you hadn't stepped in,
this would have ended up
being just like any other park!
I'm sure the audience would
have understood your reasons!
Most of all,
what infuriates me is how those
MPs tarnished your honour!
[WHITELEY laughs]
Come now, "my honour"?
Saving it was never the
priority. Forget all that.
Look, they're here.
[MARCUS]
Hm?
[WHITELEY]
My guests of honour have arrived
and are enjoying the grounds.
[CHILDREN laughing]
[BOY 19A]
This is brilliant!
They made sure the entire
estate was built on one level!
So we should be
safe playing out here!
[BOY 19A] Hey! I'll race
you over to that tree!
[CARETAKER 19A]
Children, children!
Stop being reckless!
You don't mean...
This is the vision I strove for.
Seeing the smiles
on their faces.
[CHILDREN laugh]
[WHITELEY]
Based on their expressions,
I've achieved my goal.
Now I see.
[CHILDREN laughing]
[WHITELEY grunts]
Aren't you...?
Why, Lord Moriarty.
Quite a lovely day. Wouldn't
you agree, Mister Whiteley?
Forgive my abruptness,
but I'd like to have a word.
[WHITELEY]
Tell me, Lord Moriarty,
seeing how you are a member
of the House of Lords,
why would you wish
to speak with me?
Well, actually, I have a request
that only you can fulfil.
What is this?
[ALBERT] Exactly what
you need at this moment:
Irrefutable proof
linking the House of Lords
with known mobsters.
[gasps]
[ALBERT] As long as
you have these documents,
you'll be able to conduct
your backroom dealings.
Why would you trust me
with something so incendiary
when it compromises you?
[ALBERT] You may find
this difficult to believe,
but regarding how the
House of Lords operates,
I've grown, shall
we say, disenchanted.
And besides, based on
everything I've witnessed,
I'm certain it won't be used
for nefarious purposes.
Once I made that determination,
I decided to entrust it to you.
I see.
[ALBERT] Hm. As long as your
character remains uncorrupted,
you will have my continued
support. That is all.
I really do find him to be
quite a pleasant man, William.
Thanks to the ceremony
that you orchestrated,
we were able to make certain
Mister Whiteley's
humanity was intact.
Indeed. However, this power
we've handed to him...
It was a difficult decision
that had to be made--
for him to accept the documents,
but also for us to provide them.
Though, if we had
chosen to do nothing,
without this newfound influence,
he would surely be eliminated.
When it comes to the cost
of meeting an objective,
there's always
a price to be paid.
All the more true
when it comes to
the colossal goal of
transforming this nation.
Am I right?
[WILLIAM]
Yes, you are, Brother.
Shall we?
[POLICEMAN 19D]
No! Wait! I did as you said!
I killed the criminal
who went after Whiteley!
What more do you want?
Please, spare me!
[HARRY]
Very good.
As per Mister Milverton's
instructions,
we're to make sure that this
officer's body is never found.
Dump him somewhere suitable.
As for our next target...
Heh. The MP's brother,
little Sam Whiteley.
[LESTRADE] Next time on
Moriarty the Patriot  :
"The White Knight
of London, Act Two."